One year before the Spring Festival,
قبل عيد الربيع
when my first love happened to be there.
من الجيد أن الحب الأول موجود
It's the New Year's Gala after the meeting.
بعد الاجتماع سنحتفل بالسنة الجديدة
It looks like
يبدو أن هذا العام
we're gonna celebrate the New Year together.
سنحتفل بعيد ميلادنا معا
Yeah.
‫صحيح
Captain Lu,
‫أيها القائد لو
we found something suspicious
‫بالقرب من سلة القمامة في الفناء الخلفي
by the trash can in the backyard.
في سلة القمامة الخلفية
We've checked it with a detector,
لقد أجرينا جهاز الكشف
and there's something wrong.
هناك شيء
Evacuate the crowd first.
لنفرق الجمهور أولا
Yes, sir.
حاضر
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
They said nothing about it.
لم أقل
Let's go out first.
لنخرج أولا
It might be a fire drill.
ربما يكون تدريب الحريق
A bomb that explodes as the pressure on it is gone.
القنبلة
It has a simple structure.
تصميم بسيط
A large part
داخل القنبلة
inside the bomb
‫مساحة كبيرة جدا
may hold clues about the perpetrator.
قد يكون هناك أدلة للقاتل
To protect these clues
‫من أجل الحفاظ على الأدلة‬
and trace the manufacturer,
من أجل الحفاظ على الأدلة
I suggest on-site demolition.
أقترح إلغاء المكان
The crowd has been evacuated.
لقد انفصلت الجمهور
We agree on the on-site demolition.
وافقت على تفكيك المكان
Sir,
أيها الرفاق
what's going on inside?
ماذا يحدث بالداخل؟
Nothing.
لا شيء
Just a routine check.
فحص روتيني
We're just waiting here.
انتظر
Why don't we take a walk around?
ما رأيك أن نتجول بالقرب من هنا؟
It seems that...
يبدو
According to my earlier search,
لقد بحثت من قبل
there's a rice noodle restaurant nearby
هناك مطعم معكرونة الأرز بالقرب من هنا
which is super famous.
مشهور جدا
How about this?
‫كيف هذا‬
Luosifen.
‫مسحوق الحلزون‬
Not bad.
‫حسنا‬
Let's eat first.
لنذهب لتناول الطعام
Let's go.
لنذهب
Go.
هيا
The detonator is successfully removed.
تم إزالة جهاز الانفجار بنجاح
Congratulations, guys.
مبروك للجميع
You can go back to celebrate the New Year.
يمكنكم العودة للاحتفال بعيد الربيع
Did your first love know it?
هل تعرف الحب الأول
Nope.
لا أعرف
We had broken up at that time.
‫انفصلنا منذ وقت طويل
Captain Lu,
‫فريق لو
what does your first love look like?
كيف هو الحب الأول
A couple of days ago,
قبل يومين
the test scores came out.
حصلت على نتيجة الاختبار.
Yours was not high.
درجتك ليست عالية
You shouldn't have asked about his first love.
‏من طلب منك السؤال عن الحب الأول؟‏
I've made an appointment
‏لديّ موعد‏
It's 3 p.m.
اليوم الثامن
on the 8th day of the first lunar month.
الساعة الثالثة بعد الظهر
You come to pick me up first that day.
‫جئت لتأخذني في ذلك اليوم
See you at 1 p.m.
تحت بيت عمتي
downstairs at my aunt's house.
أراك في الساعة الواحدة بعد الظهر
Are you in a relationship?
هل وقعت في الحب
You look distracted by your phone.
‫لا أستطيع أن أحمل الهاتف‬
Nah.
لا
You look just like a single man.
من الواضح أنه ليس لديه عائلة
Those in our team who have wives
لدينا زوجة في فريقنا
always report their safety
بمجرد عودتنا
to their wives by phone when they come back.
وأخبر زوجتي بأمان بمجرد عودتهم
Or the wives will surely be mad when they return home.
‫وإلا ستغضب عندما نعود إلى المنزل
Lu Chen,
‫لو تشين
you are busier and busier
‫عملك الآن
with your work now.
مشغول أكثر فأكثر
You still work your socks off during the Spring Festival.
‫في رأس السنة الجديدة
The Spring Festival is the busiest time.
‫أنا مشغول في السنة الجديدة
Go ahead.
اذهب للعمل
You've had enough fun outside.
لقد تعبت في الخارج بما فيه الكفاية
And you still know to come back, huh?
كيف تجرؤ على العودة
Can I have a good talk
هل يمكنني التحدث معك
with you today?
أن أتحدث معك
I just want you to get married
أريدك أن تتزوج
instead of doing
لم أطلب منك أن تفعل
anything evil.
أشياء شريرة
But do you have to
هل أنت جاد؟
treat me like this?
تعاملني هكذا
You really embarrass me.
لا تحترمني
How old are you?
كم عمرك
Are you gonna remain single forever?
‫هل تخططين ألا تتزوجي طوال حياتك؟
Hey, Lu.
‫لو،
He has been on duty for days before returning home.
‫لقد عاد الطفل في الخدمة لعدة أيام
He worked so hard.
ليس سهلا
So did we!
من سهل
Did anyone
منذ صغرنا
ever take care of us in our childhood?
من قبل؟
I raised him with food,
كل ما أريد
but he doesn't listen to me when he has grown up.
لا تستمع إلي عندما تكبر
Is that reasonable?
هل هذا معقول
You once served in the police force.
لقد كنت في الشرطة
Filial piety is paramount among all virtues,
‫كل الخير هو الأهم
and filial piety is everything.
الولاء هو الوالدين
Your father, who was a police officer,
والدك كشرطي
also taught you a lot, right?
علمك كثيرا
Why are you
كلما كبرت
even more immature as you grow older?
كلما كنت لا تفهم الأمور البشرية
Think carefully.
فكري جيداً
We still owe money to the Zhaos.
يجب أن نأخذ أموال عائلة تشاو
I'll pay them back.
سأعيد أموال عائلة تشاو
You don't have to pay even a cent.
لا داعي أن تدفع
D-Do you know
هل تعرف
how much money we owe them?
كم يجب أن يدفع؟
I know.
أعرف
That's good.
هذا جيد
I can do nothing to help.
لا يمكنني مساعدتك
You're pretty tough now.
أنت عنيد
I knew it was worthwhile to bring my son up.
‫قلت أن ابني ليس بلا جدوى
Lu Chen,
‫لو تشين
even if you
‫حتى لو كنت
hold a great grudge against me,
تجاهي
you should come back for dinner once in a while.
يجب أن تعود لتناول العشاء
Your mom is still at home, anyway.
بعد كل شيء أمك لا تزال في المنزل
Besides, I'm quite good
علاوة على ذلك
at cooking.
لا بأس به
Tell me what you wanna eat
متى ستعود؟ ماذا تريد أن تأكل؟
before you come back
قل لي مقدما
so that I can prepare in advance.
حتى أستعد مقدما
Would you like something to eat?
هل ستأكل أم لا
No.
لا
Let me sleep for three hours first.
دعني أنام لمدة ثلاث ساعات
I have something else to do in the afternoon.
لدي عمل بعد الظهر
Okay.
حسنا
Get me
‫جهز لي مجموعة‬
a formal suit
بدلة رسمية
I'll wear it then.
ارتدي ملابس العمل
You're going to see your future father-in-law.
سأذهب لمقابلة والد المستقبل
Alright... I'll stop here.
حسنًا حسنًا حسنًا   لن نتحدث
Why are you so shy?
أنت خجول
Here, take it.
خذ
Let me think.
دعني أفكر
I'll get you the most expensive one
سأجد لك أجمل مجموعة
and iron it for you.
سأحرق لك
I don't need the most expensive one.
لا تحتاج أغلى شيء
Just gimme a medium-priced suit.
‫من المستوى الوسط‬
It's not your clothes.
ليس ملابسك
So it's up to me.
أنا المسؤول
Why did you come in a suit?
لماذا تغيرت بدلة
I'll meet Gui Xiao later.
أراك لاحقاً
No wonder.
ما زلت أشعر بالفضول
She came
جاءت إلى هنا
with the loan contract.
إلى هنا
Go inside and sign it.
ادخلي وقعي
And then leave the rest to me.
‫اترك الباقي لي
Lu Chen.
‫لو تشين
Can I
‫هل يمكنني
talk to him alone?
بمفردي؟
This time,
هذه المرة
I did something wrong.
‫فعلت شيئا خاطئا‬
But I want to marry you
لكني أريد أن أتزوجك
sincerely.
أنا صادق
I've never ever
منذ البداية إلى النهاية
had any feelings for you.
لم أفكر بك
This is the first time
منذ التخرج
we've met alone
هذه أول مرة
since our graduation.
نلتقي بمفردنا
Xiaoshan,
الأخت شياو شان
Hai Dong and I...
أنا وهاي دونغ
That was just a childhood thing.
كنا صغاراً
It's meaningless to talk about it again.
‫لا فائدة من ذكر ذلك
No matter what feelings
‫مهما كنت
you have for Lu Chen,
‫تجاه لو تشين
it's time to end them today.
حان وقت الانتهاء اليوم
Everyone knows what kind of person
من هو والده؟
his father is.
‫لا أحد لا يعرف
But Lu Chen grew up
‫لكن لو تشين
without wronging anyone,
‫لم يشعر بالأسف لأحد
and neither did he ever
ولم أفعل أي شيء
fail you, Zhao Minshan.
على تشاو مين شان
From beginning to end,
من البداية إلى النهاية
you've been up to something.
لم تفعل شيئا جيدا
That's the end of this affair.
انتهى هذا الأمر
You two families
أنتما الاثنان
are no more than the creditor and the debtor.
علاقتكما بالدين والسداد
If you still don't get it,
إذا لم تتمكن من معرفة ذلك
I'll get even with you from that year.
سأبدأ معك من تلك السنة
Get in.
اركبي السيارة
I don't have any formal clothes.
ليس لدي ملابس رسمية
So I'm wearing Hai Dong's suit.
ارتدي ملابس هادونغ
Is it okay for me to meet the class adviser like this?
هل هناك مشكلة في مقابلة مشرف الصف
Sure.
‏لا مشكلة‏
It's my first time
هذه أول مرة
seeing you in a suit.
رأيتك ترتدي بدلة
I feel kind of weird.
غريب
I'm not used to it, too.
لست معتادة على ذلك
This place is still the same as before,
هذا المكان لا يزال كما كان من قبل
without any change,
لا يوجد تغيير
Nothing has changed.
‫لم يتغير‬
Captain Lu.
‫فريق لو
Hello, I've heard a lot about you...
‫تشرفت بلقائك تشرفت بلقائك
Hello.
مرحبا
To get to know you,
من أجل أن أعرفك
I've searched all over the Internet for your interviews.
بحثت في تقرير مقابلتك عبر الإنترنت
What a pity that there's only one article.
من المؤسف أن هناك مقال واحد فقط
A great hero like you
أنتم بطل كبير
should be promoted more.
يجب أن تقوم بالترويج أكثر
Enough.
يكفي
Sorry, Captain Lu.
‫معذرة أيها القائد لو
My husband
زوجي
just pretends to be passionate.
إنه يتظاهر بالحماس
He's excited in front of others.
الناس مجنونون
How can you say I pretend to be passionate?
كيف يمكن أن تقول إنني أتظاهر بالحب
This is my sister's first love.
هذا الحب الأول لأختي
Let's get down to business first.
لنبدأ العمل أولاً
Okay.
‏حسناً‏
This class adviser
‫هذا المشرف
is an old teacher,
إنها معلمة قديمة
who's very responsible.
مسؤولة جدا
She specifically asked to meet
وقال خصيصًا أنه يريد مقابلة
the Xiaonan's parents first
والديه
just to know the kid's
لمعرفة
study and life conditions
عن حالة الحياة
and other things like personality.
والأشياء الأخرى
I already called her
لقد اتصلت بها
in advance,
من قبل
and told her the kid's parents
قال والدا الأطفال
were not in Beijing.
ليس في بكين
Just go upstairs and feel free to talk to her.
يمكنكم التحدث في الأعلى
Anyway, it's all for Xiaonan
على أي حال من أجل الطفل
to get used to the new school life
لتعود على
as soon as possible.
حياة الانتقال
Okay, thank you.
حسنا شكرا
It's all my husband's fault.
كل هذا بسبب زوجي
I forgot to introduce myself.
‫نسيت أن أقدم نفسي‬
My name is Xia Xia,
‫اسمي شيا شيا‬
and I'm Gui Xiao's sister-in-law.
هو ابن عمه
He is Wen Cheng,
اسمه ون تشنغ
Gui Xiao's cousin.
إنه ابن عمها
Let's go upstairs.
اصعد
Okay.
حسناً
Gui Xiao's first love
الحب الأول
is so handsome
تبدو جميلة جدا
with a good figure.
تبدو جميلة
That's enough...
يكفي يكفي
Do you think they still have a chance?
هل تعتقد أن لديهما فرصة؟
I think so.
أظن ذلك
Coming.
‫أنا قادمة‬
Hello.
مرحبا
Mom!
أمي
Mom, we have some guests.
أمي، لدينا ضيف
Sister. brother-in-law, come here.
‫تعال يا فينغ تاي
Come in, please. No need to change your shoes.
‫ادخلوا بسرعة لا داعي لتغيير حذائك
Do you know her?
هل تعرفه؟
Hello, Mrs. Sun.
سيد صن
Hello.
مرحباً
This is Qin Xiaonan's uncle,
‫هذا هو العم تشين شياو نان‬
Lu Yanchen,
‫لو يان تشن‬
the one I mentioned to you
‫في الهاتف
on the phone.
في الهاتف
He just came back from Qining.
لقد عاد للتو من تشي نينغ
Come in, please.
تعال ادخل
Feel free to take your seats.
تفضلي بالجلوس
Sister,
أختي
he was the SWAT officer I talked about back then.
‫كان هو الشرطي الخاص الذي ذكرته في ذلك الوقت‬
Excuse me.
من فضلك
Were you a SWAT officer before?
هل كنت شرطي خاص؟
Yes.
نعم
And so am I now.
الآن
We thought you changed your job
رأيتك ترتدي بدلة
when we saw you in a suit.
ظننت أنك غيرت المهنة
Do I look familiar to you?
هل أنا مألوف؟
It's normal that he doesn't know you.
من الطبيعي ألا يعرفك
Just a few years ago,
قبل بضع سنوات
my sister and her classmate
أختي وزملائها
went on a graduation trip
في رحلة التخرج
and encountered bad weather,
وعندما واجهت الطقس السيئ
when we were trapped on the mountain, unable to get down.
لا يمكنني النزول من الجبل
Quite a lot of SWAT officers went to help us
جاء العديد من الشرطة الخاصة للمساعدة
go down the mountain.
لمساعدتنا في النزول من الجبل
Do you remember that?
هل تتذكر
My classmate had straight hair,
زميلي في الصف مباشر
which was so long
طويل جدا
to the waist.
‫إلى خصري‬
I had curly hair,
‫أنا حلقة الشعر‬
long brown and curly hair.
‫شعر طويل اللون‬
I don't remember.
لا أتذكر
He carries out tasks every day.
إنها تنفذ المهمة كل يوم
Who knows how many people
لا أعرف كم من الناس سيساعدون
he has helped and saved?
كم عدد الناس
You are just one of them.
أنت واحد من الجمهور
I just feel it's so rare.
أنا فقط أعتقد أنه نادر جدا
Thank you.
شكرا لك
Seriously.
حقا
Thank you so much.
شكرا
This is my duty,
هذا واجبي
Mom, here you are
تعالي يا أمي
Here.
تعالي
This is the winter vacation homework.
هذا واجب عطلة الشتاء
Bring it back.
خذها
Xiaonan doesn't have to finish it all.
لا تحتاج إلى إنهاء كل الأطفال
I just want him to get used to
فقط للتكيف
the mode
وضع الواجبات
of our winter vacation homework.
في عطلة الشتاء
Just help him assimilate first.
أولاً
We'll leave Xiaonan to you
فيما بعد شياو نان
from now on.
‫سأتركها لك
To quote your lines,
‫استخدم كلام الكابتن لو
this is my duty,
‫هذا واجبي
so don't mention it.
هذا واجبي
Thank you.
شكرا لك
Do you really have no memory of it?
لا أتذكر حقا
I remember the mission and the time,
لدي انطباع عن المهمة والمكان
but not the people.
لا
That mission came all of a sudden,
تلك المهمة فجأة
and our entire team went there.
لقد مر فريقنا بأكمله
The squadron of police dogs
فريق الكلاب الشرطي
was also searching for people everywhere on the mountain.
يبحثون عن الناس
There were hundreds of tourists
كان السياح في المنطقة السياحية
in the scenic back then,
هناك مئات الأصدقاء الحمار
some of whom went really deep.
بعض الناس مشوا بعمق
After several hours of search and rescue,
لبضعة ساعات من البحث والإنقاذ
we searched all over the mountain.
يبحثون في كل مكان
So I couldn't remember those faces at all.
لا أتذكر وجه الناس على الإطلاق
High winds, hypothermia, the narrow mountain roads,
الرياح العاصفة فقدت الحرارة والطريق الضيق
and a large number of tourists.
هناك الكثير من السياح
In this case,
في هذه الحالة
we had no time
ليس لدينا وقت
to care about
أن نهتم بشخص ما
different people's faces,
ما الفرق
or whether it was the long hair or the curly hair.
هل هو شعر طويل أم شعر مجعد
You're right.
صحيح
When I was in high school,
عندما كنت في المدرسة الثانوية
I often went shopping here.
كنت آتي إلى هنا للتسوق كثيرًا
In addition to this place,
والآخر هنا
I also went to the clothing wholesale market
والآخر بجانب حديقة الحيوانات
next to the zoo.
بجانب حديقة الحيوانات
One of my cousins was really good at bargaining.
لدي ابنة عمي يمكنها خصم السعر
Every time when I brought her out,
في كل مرة أخرجها
I could save a lot of money.
يوفر الكثير من المال
The cousin you met today
ابن عمك الذي قابلته اليوم
was a follower when he was little.
كان تابعاً في طفولته
We didn't want to play with him.
لا نريد أن نلعب معه
So he just cried and complained to others.
لكنه يبكي ويشكوى
Are these things
أنت الآن
unfamiliar to you
هل تشعرين
now?
غريب جدا
I haven't come back
منذ المدرسة الثانوية
During the years in Qining,
في تشي نينغ هذه السنوات
I've been back
في تشي نينغ
less than five times.
لم يتجاوز خمس مرات
Actually, I don't know much
في الواقع بالنسبة إلى بكين الحالي
about today's Beijing
بين بكين الحالي
just like Qin Xiaonan.
بين تشين شياو نان
Welcome home.
مرحباً بعودتك إلى المنزل
My brother's car is missing.
لقد اختفى سيارتي
The traffic is too congested.
ازدحام جدا
We can't find them now.
لا يمكنني العثور عليه الآن
Let's contact them when we get there.
سنتواصل بعد الوصول
Actually, out of the only five times,
في الواقع في خمسة مرات فقط
I did it twice to see you.
‫مرتين لزيارتك‬
Why was it only once in my memory?
لماذا أتذكر مرة واحدة فقط
You came back
عندما كنت في الجامعة
And when you asked to break up with me.
وأيضا المرة التي ذكرت الانفصال
Did you come back at that time?
لقد عدت
I'm calling my brother
سأتصل بأخي
to see if they've arrived.
لأرى إذا وصلوا أم لا
Call them in five minutes.
سنتصل بعد خمس دقائق
OK.
حسناً
The thing concerning Zhao Minshan
لقد انتهى أمر تشاو مين شان
is over.
انتهى
You look so happy.
أنت سعيد جدا
Of course.
بالطبع سعيد
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
لماذا لم تخبرني مبكرا
I had something serious to do with you this afternoon.
‫سأتعامل معك في العمل بعد الظهر
So it was improper to talk about it.
من الصعب القول
This is also a serious matter.
هذا أمر مهم أيضا
Gui Xiao.
عودوا
They've arrived.
لقد وصلوا
Let's get off.
انزل من السيارة بسرعة
Are you out of your mind again?
هل فقدت عقلك مرة أخرى؟
I just subconsciously...
لقد أدركت
My sinful hand...
يدي
Sister, I didn't recognize
‫لا أعرفك يا أختي
Chen's car just now.
‫إنها سيارة تشين
That's why I honked.
‫لذا ضغطت على مكبر الصوت
Never mind, but why are you so nervous?
فلتضغط على ذلك لماذا أنت متوتر
Let's go up from here.
هيا، من هنا
Sister,
أختي
are you going to
هل أنتِ مستعدة
spend a lot of money today、
تنزف كثيرا
Order whatever you want today.
اطلبي ما تشائين اليوم
It's on me.
كما تشاؤون
Is there a budget limit?
هل هناك ميزانية محدودة
A month's salary.
سأعطيك راتب شهر
Is it enough?
هل يكفي؟
I'll take a good look then.
يجب أن ألقي نظرة
Hello.
مرحبا
We'd like to order this.
أعطنا نسخة
OK.
حسنا
How much of this
ما هي
do you have today?
‫ما هو وزنك اليوم‬
There's only one kilogram left.
‫هذا وزن كيلو فقط‬
That should be enough for four people.
يجب أن يكون أربعة أشخاص كافيين
I'll go check it with you later.
سأذهب معك بعد قليل
Okay.
حسنا
And this one, too.
هذه أيضا
The dishes here
أطباقه هنا
are all offered
وفقاً لليوم
at the day's supply price,
سعر التوصيل
just to keep them fresh.
أريد أن تكون طازجة
Table 13.
الطاولة رقم 13
Check, please.
ادفع الحساب
Just a minute, sir.
انتظر لحظة يا سيدي
Waiter, may I have the bill, please?
أيها النادل، ادفع الفاتورة
The gentleman who just left
الرجل الذي خرج للتو
has paid the bill.
قد دفع الحساب
Could you please show me the bill?
دعني أرى الفاتورة
Okay, please hold on a moment.
حسنا انتظر قليلا
Hello, madam.
مرحباً سيدتي
Captain Lu is quite generous!
‫قوة فريق لو جيدة
Sister,
أختي
your first love
إن حبك الأول
is from a rich family, right?
هل ظروف الاقتصاد في المنزل جيدة
Waiter,
أيها النادل
please pack
من فضلك ساعديني
the rest of the food for me.
هذه الأطباق
Okay.
حسنا
Thank you.
شكرا
Get down to work.
اعمل
This is the winter vacation homework
هذه مدرسة جديدة
assigned by your new school.
من المدرسة الجديدة
Although the teacher didn't ask you
على الرغم من أن المعلم لم يطلب
to finish it all,
أن تنهي كل شيء
you still should do it all
لكن ليس لديك شيء مؤخرًا
since you're free recently.
يجب أن تفعل كل شيء
Don't slack off.
لا تتكاسل
I'm going to dismantle some cars.
سأهدم بعض العربات
Go to bed if you're sleepy.
نم إذا كنت تشعر بالنعاس
I'll sleep next door.
سأنام في الغرفة المجاورة
Some cars?
كم سيارة
I can only see him tomorrow morning indeed.
يجب أن نلتقي صباح الغد
Luckily, your family
لحسن الحظ
run a garage.
تدير مصنع إصلاح السيارة
There you are.
أنت هنا
The barbecue I ate was quite good.
أنا آكل هذه السلسلة جيدة
So I've packed some for the kid.
حزمي طبقا للطفل
You don't look like you're in trouble.
لا يبدو أنك وقعت في مشكلة
You look good!
تبدو بخير
Why are you dismantling the cars?
لماذا هدم السيارة
I see.
فهمت
You disassemble cars whether you're happy
أنت سعيد وتهدم السيارة
or sad, right?
‫أو حزينة
Chen.
‫تشين
I just came back from a business trip,
‫عدت للتو من رحلة عمل
and my brother told me you were transferred to Beijing.
سمعت أخي يقول أنك انتقلت إلى بكين
So I followed him to see you right away.
لذا جئت معه لرؤيتك
Good.
حسنا أخي
You haven't changed a bit over the years.
لم تتغير منذ سنوات عديدة
You haven't changed either.
لم تتغير
I just finished my homework.
لقد أنهيت الواجبات للتو
I'm going to bed.
سأنام أولا
Go ahead.
‫اذهبي
Is he your kid, Chen?
‫هذا طفلك يا تشين
No.
‫لا
It's my friend's.
صديق
I thought you got married
اعتقدت أنك في تشي نينغ
in Qining.
في تشي نينغ
Nah.
‫ما الزواج‬
He's waiting for Gui Xiao.
إنهم ينتظرون عودتهم
Stop talking nonsense.
ما هذا الهراء؟
Other people may have no idea about it,
لا أحد يعرف
but I know.
‏لا أعرف‏
Gui Xiao in our class?
‏(غوي شياو)‏
Of course. Who else can it be?
‫هراء، من غيره؟
Chen and Gui Xiao were once in a relationship?
‫تشين وشياو بخير
They
‫إنهما
fell in love after graduation.
بعد التخرج
Many people don't know that.
الكثير من الناس لا يعرفون
Why didn't you tell me?
لماذا لم تخبرني؟
Why should I tell you?
لماذا أخبرك؟
What are you looking at?
‫إلى ماذا تنظر؟
Pour Chen a drink.
‫اسكب النبيذ لأخيك تشين
No.
‫لا أشرب
It's my shift tomorrow afternoon, so I can't drink.
لا يمكنني الشرب بعد الظهر غدًا
Don't drink directly with the bottle.
لا تهب الزجاجة
How can I drink it in this case?
كيف سأشرب هكذا
Pour it into the glass.
اشرب في الكأس
Help yourself.
‫اسكب بنفسك أنا
I'm so happy to see Chen.
‫أنا سعيد جداً برؤية تشين
Here you are, Chen.
‫تعال يا تشين
I won't drink.
‫لا أشرب
He already said that.
قلت لك لا تشرب
Thank you.
شكراً لك يا أخي
I'm fine.
أنا بخير يا أخي
Go continue to talk to my brother.
اذهب وتحدث مع أخي
Thank you, Chen.
‫شكراً يا تشين
Leave him alone.
‫اتركه وشأنه
Just let him throw up.
دعه يتقيأ
He'll be fine after that.
سيتعافى بعد التقيؤ
Come back and sit.
عد واجلس
Sit.
اجلس
His condition
أرى حالته
reminds me of my past.
تذكرت في ذلك الوقت
When Meng Xiaoshan got married,
‫يوم زفاف منغ شياو شان‬
I almost
كدت
drank to death in front of their house.
كدت أموت أمام منزلهم
And in the next half a year,
‫في نصف عام
I shed all my tears
دموعي
of half my life.
طوال حياتي
Have you ever cried
هل بكيت من قبل؟
for Gui Xiao?
من أجل العودة
It also counts if you cried secretly.
‫البكاء سرا
Have you cried for her?
هل فعلت ذلك من قبل؟
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Since you already said it,
بما أنك قلت ذلك
just finish the story.
فلتكمل كلامك
She wanted to break up with me.
قالت الانفصال
I called her over and over again.
اتصلت بها مرارا وتكرارا
She hung up every time.
لقد أغلقت الخط مرارا وتكرارا
She didn't even let me
حتى نصف جملة
Then I didn't dare to call her.
بعد ذلك لم أجرؤ على ضربها
I was afraid she would be scolded by her family if I called too many times.
خشيت أن يتم توبيخها من قبل عائلتها
Half a year after our breakup,
بعد نصف عام انفصلنا
I finally had a chance to return to Beijing.
وأخيرا لدي فرصة للعودة إلى بكين
And I had to leave the next day.
سأعود في اليوم التالي
That night,
تلك الليلة
she still refused to meet me.
لا تزال ترفض رؤيتي
I didn't go home.
لم أعود إلى المنزل
I stayed at the train station until dawn,
في محطة القطار حتى الفجر
and then left directly.
غادرت مباشرة
I'm in Beijing.
أنا في بكين
Let's go out to meet.
خرجت لمقابلة
Forget about it.
انسي الأمر
You came back after you broke up, huh?
لقد عدت بعد الانفصال
I know you're single-minded.
أعلم أنك مخلص
But I didn't expect
لكن لم أتوقع
you to have such deep feelings for Gui Xiao.
أن لديك مشاعر عميقة تجاه جوى شياو
I should go back.
يجب أن أعود
Wake up.
استيقظ
Let's go.
لنذهب
I'll pick up Qin Xiaonan tomorrow.
سآتي غدا لأخذ تشين شياو نان
I have to send Hai Jianfeng back first.
يجب أن أعيد هاي جيان فينج أولاً
His mom really loves him.
والدته تحبه
If he doesn't return in the middle of the night,
إذا لم تعد في منتصف الليل
she'll scold either him or me.
إذا لم توبخه فستوبخني
See you.
سأذهب
Go ahead.
‫اذهب
Chen,
‫تشين
wish you two all the best.
‫أتمنى لكما السعادة
Did you buy it?
هل اشتريتها؟
Who else could it be other than me?
من غيري
Aunt Gui Xiao, of course!
العمة جوى شياو
You're not related to her.
أنت لست قريبة منه
Dare you take it at will?
كيف تجرؤ على أخذها؟
No.
أنا آسف
So,
لذلك
I'm writing it down.
لقد سجلت الحساب
When I make money,
بعد أن أكسب المال
I'll take inflation into account
وحسب التسليم
and pay her back together.
سنعيدها معا
Good.
هذا أفضل
But remember,
لكن تذكر
you need skills to pay her back.
يجب أن يكون هناك مهارات
Don't break her heart.
لا تؤذي قلبها
Of course.
بالطبع
Let me see.
دعني أرى
You're about to be as handsome as me.
أفضل مني نصف
What a narcissist.
هراء
I can't buy you clothes of really good brands
لقد جمعت المال خلال هذين العامين
since I've been saving money these years.
لا يمكنني شراء العلامة التجارية الجيدة لك
But,
لكن
new clothes for Chinese New Year.
يجب أن يكون هناك ملابس جديدة في السنة الجديدة
This is the custom.
هذه هي القواعد
I know.
أعلم
Let's go and eat.
اذهبي لتناول الطعام
This is your Aunt Gui Xiao's
هذه عمة جوى شياو
favorite restaurant
في المدرسة
I want to eat what she likes.
أريد أن آكل ما تأكله عادة
Is this your son?
هذا ابنك
No.
لا
My nephew.
ابن أخي
I thought you got married
اعتقدت أنك تزوجت
with that girl and had this kid.
تزوجت وأنجبت
Which girl?
أي فتاة
You know what?
أنت لا تعرف
Your uncle
عمك
always brought that girl
كان يأخذ تلك الفتاة
to eat noodles here before.
لتناول المعكرونة
She looked so pretty,
تبدو جميلة جدا
and was really good at eating spicy food.
إنه فقط يأكل الطعام الحار
She ate one bowl of noodles
تناول وعاء من المعكرونة
with half a bottle of spicy sauce.
تناول نصف زجاجة صلصة الفلفل
It was summer,
في الصيف
and even I was sweating when I saw her eating.
أرى أنها تتعرق عندما تأكل
Same as usual.
كالعادة
Two bowls.
وعاءان
Okay.
حسنا
Just a moment.
انتظر
What?
ماذا
Don't you want to take the chance
‫في مهرجان الربيع
of the Spring Festival
ألا تريدين
to invite Aunt Gui Xiao to hang out?
أن تأتي مع العمة جوى شياو للتجول
Mind your own business
هل يجب عليك
instead of ours.
هل يجب أن تقلق
Were it not for
لولا
Aunt Gui Xiao,
لعمة جوى شياو
I wouldn't care about you.
لا أهتم بك
Here are your noodles.
المعكرونة هنا
Enjoy your meal.
استمتع
Thank you.
شكرا
Are you busy?
هل أنت مشغول
I'm off today.
اليوم إجازة
Are you...
أنت
How is Qin Xiaonan doing?
هل تشين شياو نان بخير؟
He said
قال
he missed you.
اشتقت إليك
Me too.
أنا أيضاً
I'll take him to see you.
سآخذه لرؤيتك
Don't bother.
لا داعي
I'll go to meet him,
جئت لرؤيته
and visit Meng Xiaoshan by the way.
‫لزيارة منغ شياو شان‬
Your reward.
مكافأتك